Phone: (214) 864-606 | Portfolio: https://pkennedytx1.com

Email: pkennedytx1@gmail.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/pkennedytx1

PATRICK KENNEDY

OBJECTIVE

I'm a software engineer with the aptitude to learn quickly, admit defeat, and seek help when necessary. Team cohesiveness is a cornerstone of my work philosophy and I am hungry to dive in and get my hands dirty on the tasks others are hesitant to take on. With leadership and development experience, along with a unique background, I am searching for an opportunity to join a development team as an entry-level engineer.

TECHNOLOGIES

HTML5, CSS3, React, Javascript, Node, Express, MongoDB, NoSQL, SQL, Ruby on Rails, GraphQL, Agile, Git, Firebase, REST API, Bootstrap, Materialize, jQuery

PROJECTS

Task Trader - MongoDB, Express, React, Node, GraphQL

Github: https://github.com/nolanglenn/project3

Deployed Project: https://task-trader.herokuapp.com/

- This web application was built in a team of 4 in week long sprints within a 3 week time frame.
- My contribution to the project was the login and authentication as well as most of the front end development. As a team we learned and implemented GraphQL into the application within the time span of the project.

Morning Coffee - SQL, Express, Node

Github: https://github.com/theAndes/Project-2

Deployed Project: https://morning-coffee-project-2.herokuapp.com/

- This web application was built in a team of 4 organized around a week of work.
- Debugging on an hourly basis to help students conquer problems and better understand the methods for troubleshooting so they are working smarter and not harder.

Personal Portfolio – https://pkennedytx1.com

Checkout some of my other work as well as my professional work on my portfolio website.

OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

Dev Launchers — https://devlaunchers.com/

EXPERIENCE

Flatiron x WeWork, Austin TX — Software Engineering Coach

September 2019 - PRESENT

- Worked with students in an Agile environment helping them learn concepts and apply them to their projects while maintaining positive mindsets and supporting positive growth.
- Debugging on an hourly basis to help students conquer problems and better understand the methods for troubleshooting so they are working smarter and not harder.

Software Engineer Freelancer, Austin TX – Software Engineer

December 2018 - PRESENT

- Worked with clients to produce sites that enhance their business needs while staying within budget.
- Problem solving to create functional and secure sites with blogs, payment processors, and database storage. Thinking outside of the box to make a great website to fit the need of a customer and their budget.

EDUCATION

University of Texas — Software Engineering Bootcamp

NOVEMBER 2018 - APRIL 2019, Austin TX

Learning the MERN stack along with trying new technologies like GraphQL and Redux launched my career as a software engineer. Inspiring a deep hunger to learn and grow everyday as a developer. This bootcamp challenged my teamwork skills and my perception of what it means to learn resulting in personal and professional growth.

Texas A&M University – BS Molecular and Cellular Biology

AUGUST 2014 - MAY 2018, College Station TX

Python programming in genomics led me to want to learn more about programming. Ask me about how the concepts of molecular biology apply to computer science and software development, you might be surprised.